Guide to the First Congregational Church of Portland records 1849-2016
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
First Congregational Church of Portland records
1849-2016
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
Coll 597
First Congregational Church of Portland (Or.)
70.2 cubic feet 113 document cases, 43 flat boxes, 2 card file boxes, and 51 oversize folders
Records and photographs of the First Congregational UCC church in Portland, Oregon.
The First Congregational Church of Portland was founded by Reverend Horace Lyman, who began its construction in 1850 and opened it at what is today SW Second Avenue and SW Jefferson Street on June 15, 1851. A larger church was built on the same spot in 1871. It was the third church building, though, located at SW Park and Madison, which would become best known. Completed in 1895 at considerable expense, it was one of few American churches built in the Venetian Gothic style, and for several decades it was the tallest building in Portland. This building continued to house the church into the 21st century, although some of its smaller towers were removed in 1951.
Throughout its history, the First Congregational Church has been involved in music and the arts, forming its first choir in 1856, and hosting art exhibitions as early as 1875. The church also has a history in engaging social issues. It hosted a convention for women suffragists in 1905, and in 1992 its congregation voted overwhelmingly in favor of welcoming openly gay and lesbian parishioners.
Since 1960, the First Congregational Church has been a United Church of Christ church.
The collection consists of records, correspondence, photographs, and ephemera relating to the First Congregational Church of Portland. Included are annual reports, financial records, materials regarding the church’s Sunday School, the records of various committees, commissions, and clubs that formed within the church, issues of the church’s newsletter The Pilgrim, building plans, and materials relating to the church’s activities in social action, music, theater, and visual arts. Also present are materials relating to the church’s ministers, as well as its more prominent members including Frances B. Clapp, Elizabeth Eggert, George Himes, and General Oliver O. Howard.
The materials are arranged in the following series:
Series A: General records
Series B: Groups
Series C: History and memorabilia
Series D: Membership statistics
Series E: Members
Series F: Senior Ministers
Series G: Associate Ministers
Series H: In-Care Ministers
Series I: Interim Ministers
Series J: Ordinations and installations
Series K: Lectures
Series L: Music
Series M: Performing and visual arts
Series N: Properties and facilities
Series O: Sunday School and church education
Series P: Missionary work
Series Q: Social action
Series R: Newsletters
Series S: Publicity
Series T: Interchurch and interfaith activities
Series U: Conferences and conventions
Series V: Images
Series W: Other materials and ephemera
The collection is open to the public.
Lib. Acc. 28972.
Second copy of book "That Church with the Tower: Highlights of Our History" separated to book catalogs, Oregon Historical Society Research Library.
Additional materials regarding Congregational churches in Oregon are designated Mss 1018 at Oregon Historical Society Research Library.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
First Congregational Church of Portland (Or.)--Archives; First Congregational Church of Portland (Or.)--Photographs
Atkinson, G. H. (George Henry), 1819-1889; Caldwell, Royald V., 1914-2000; Clapp, Frances Benton, 1887-1977; Eggert, Elizabeth Avery, 1848-1935; Himes, George H., 1844-1940; Howard, O. O. (Oliver Otis), 1830-1909; Lyman, Horace, 1815-1887; Reed, Lincoln Y. (Lincoln Yullie), 1921-2010; Rogers, John M. (John MacNaughton); Ross, Patricia S., 1941-.; Walker, Raymond B., 1889-1974
Portland (Or.)--Churches
Congregational churches--Oregon--Portland; Church buildings--Oregon--Portland--Photographs; Religion--Oregon--Portland; Social action--Oregon--Portland; Religious education--Oregon--Portland; Music--Oregon--Portland; Art--Oregon--Portland
Religion; Oregon; Portland
Administrative records; Correspondence; Minutes (administrative records); Ledgers (account books); Reports; Newsletters; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Photograph albums; Printed ephemera; Building plans
The Pilgrim.; That Church with the Tower: Highlights of Our History.
- General records, 1850-2015; Series A
  - American flag issue, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 1/1)
    Documents relating to a debate over whether or not to display the American flag in the church sanctuary.
  - Articles of Faith, circa 1895 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - By-laws, 1920 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - By-laws, 1920 June17 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - By-law amendments, 1920 December 23 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Note concerning notation in 1947 by-laws, undated (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Notice re by-law change, 1952 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - By-laws, circa 1955 (Box-folder 1/8)
    Includes attached copy of 1919 articles of incorporation.
  - Proposed by-law amendment, circa 1959 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - By-laws, 1963 January 15 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - By-laws, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - By-laws, 1974 March 17 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - By-law amendments, 1981 December 21 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Proposed by-law amendments, 1982 January 11 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - By-law amendments, 1982 January (Box-folder 1/15)
  - By-laws, 1986 December-1987 January (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Proposed by-laws draft, 1993 November (Box-folder 1/17)
  - By-laws, 1994 January 30 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Church growth workshop records, 1988 (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Church membership inventory survey records, 1980 (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Committee descriptions, 1988 (Box-folder 1/21)
  - Proposed amendments to constitution, 1895, undated (Box-folder 1/22)
  - Proposed amendments to constitution, 1899, undated (Box-folder 1/23)
  - Suggested constitutional amendments, 1963 January 6 (Box-folder 1/24)
  - Constitution and by-laws, 1967 (Box-folder 1/25)
  - Correspondence, Subseries 1
    - Notice to T. T. Burkhart on his election to church treasurer, 1898 December 14 (Box-folder 1/26)
    - Note to Mrs. Sorenson re her election to church membership, 1909 April 9 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - General correspondence, 1919 (Box-folder 1/28)
    - Correspondence, memos and notices, 1920 (Box-folder 1/29)
    - Letter re "Pastor's Day" service, 1938 October 8 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Thank-you note from Azalia E. Peet to Mrs. Morgan, 1941 May 28 (Box-folder 1/31)
      Had been located inbetween pages of Women's Missionary minutes book, 1918-1919.
    - Thank-you letter from John K. Hough, Goodyear Tire & Rubber Company, to Mrs. A. T. Johnson, 1949 May 27 (Box-folder 1/32)
    - Greeting cards sent by Reverend Raymond and Ruth Walker, circa 1950-1959 (Box-folder 1/33)
    - Letter from Daphne How, 1960 January 12 (Box-folder 1/34)
    - Letter from Howard H. Campbell to George Geist, 1961 May 3 (Box-folder 1/35)
    - Letters to Representative Edith Green and Senator Wayne Morse re proposed federal building, 1963 June 21 (Box-folder 1/36)
    - Memo re meeting schedule, 1981 (Box-folder 1/37)
    - Memo from Reverend Pat Ross to Tim Pollard, 2005 April 20 (Box-folder 1/38)
    - General correspondence, 2006-2014 (Box-folder 1/39)
    - Letter from Lois Lyon and enclosed 1922 church bulletin, 2015 November 24 (Box-folder 1/40)
    - Letter from Caroline H, Clapp to "Ladies of the Mission Society", undated (Box-folder 1/41)
  - The Council Manual for a Congregational Church, 1896 (Box-folder 1/42)
  - Dossal cloth issue, 1988-1997 (Box-folder 1/43)
  - Church officer election, 1921 (Box-folder 1/44)
  - Financial records, Subseries 2
    For financial documents specific to subgroups within the church, see Series B: Groups.
    - Accounting and financial reporting recommendation highlights, 2004 July 21 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Accounts, 1902 July-December (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Balance sheets, budgets, etc., 1921-1923; 1942; 1957 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Balance sheets, budgets, etc., 1972-1973 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Balance sheets, budgets, etc., 2002-2009 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Balance sheets, budgets, etc., 2010 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Balance sheets, budgets, etc., 2011 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Balance sheets, budgets, etc., 2012 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Balance sheets, budgets, etc., 2013 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Bank deposits, by name, 1891-1892 (Box-folder 112/2)
    - Correspondence and records re Beatrice Stevens Scholarship Fund, 1983-1995 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Financial records re bell tower restoration, 2014 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Board of Trustees financial correspondence, 1895-1898 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Board of Trustees financial reports, 1897-1898; undated (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Budgets, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Budget, income, etc., 1940-1941 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Revised estimate of income and budget for 1941, circa 1941 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - "Building the 1950 Budget", 1949 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Proposed 1989 budget, 1988 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Proposed budget for 1992, 1991 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Budget income and expenses, circa 2005 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Proposed 2015 budget, 2014 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Treasurer's cash book, 1888-1895 (Box-folder 115/2)
    - Treasurer's cash book, 1895-1904 (Box-folder 115/4)
    - Treasurer's petty cash book, 1899 January - 1901 March (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Treasurer's petty cash book, 1901 April - 1903 April (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Cash book, 1913 September - 1915 January (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Cash book, 1920-1925 (Box-folder 116/3)
    - Checks, 1896-1898 (Box-folder 3/2-3/4)
    - Check stub ledger, 1894-1897 (Box-folder 114/1)
    - Church Building Fund records, 1891 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Church building fund account, 1895 (Box-folder 112/3)
    - Church Building Fund - itemized bills from J. McCracken & Co., 1891-1892 (Box-folder 3/6-3/7)
    - Contributions ledger, 1891 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Contributions ledger, 1914 (Box-folder 118/1)
    - Contributions ledger, 1916 (Box-folder 118/2)
    - Contributions ledger, 1917 (Box-folder 118/3)
    - Contributions ledger, 1918 (Box-folder 118/4)
    - Contributions ledgers, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 117/1-117/2)
    - Contributions ledger, 1921 (Box-folder 117/3)
    - Contributions ledger, 1922 (Box-folder 117/4)
    - Contributions ledger, 1923 (Box-folder 117/5)
    - Contributions ledger, 1924 (Box-folder 119/1)
    - Contributions ledger, 1926 (Box-folder 119/2)
    - Contributions ledger, 1927 (Box-folder 119/3)
    - Contributions ledger, 1928 (Box-folder 119/4)
    - Contributions ledger, 1929 (Box-folder 120/1)
    - Contributions ledger, 1930 (Box-folder 120/2)
    - Contributions ledger, 1931 (Box-folder 120/3)
    - Contributions ledger, 1932 (Box-folder 120/4)
    - Contributions ledger, 1933 (Box-folder 121/1)
    - Contributions ledger, 1933 July - 1936 April (Box-folder 121/2)
    - Contributions ledger, 1936 June - 1938 December (Box-folder 121/3)
    - Disbursements ledger, 1913 June - 1920 May (Box-folder 127/3)
    - Disbursements ledger, 1913 September - 1921 January (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Disbursements ledger, 1920 June - 1923 December (Box-folder 116/2)
    - Disbursements ledger, 1946 October - 1951 (Box-folder 124/1)
    - Disbursements ledger, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 125/1)
    - Fiscal feasibility study, 1994 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - German Savings and Loan Society records re old church building, 1895-1897 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Friendship fund report for 1946, circa 1947 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Treasurer's journal, 1898-1905 (Box-folder 115/1)
    - Recommendations of Finance Commission re Former Knight Trust, 2009 December 16 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Ledger - cash receipts and insurance records, 1913 June - 1919 December (Box-folder 127/2)
    - Ledger - cash receipts and subscriptions, 1921 January - 1922 February (Box-folder 116/1)
    - Ledger - collections, pew rentals, and pledges, 1894-1895 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Ledger - disbursements and check record, 1928-1930 (Box-folder 122/2)
    - Ledger - disbursements and receipts, 1924-1927 (Box-folder 122/1)
    - Ledger - disbursements and receipts, 1930-1933 June (Box-folder 122/3)
    - Ledger - disbursements and receipts, 1939 January - 1941 December (Box-folder 123/1)
    - Ledger - disbursements; receipts, 1943 January - 1946 December; 1942 (Box-folder 123/2)
    - Ledger - disbursements and receipts, 1943 January - 1946 December (Box-folder 123/3)
    - Ledger - disbursements and receipts, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 124/2)
    - Ledger - pew rentals and pledges, 1894-1895 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Ledger, 1896-1898 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Ledger, 1898-1905 (Box-folder 115/3)
    - Ledger - receipts and contributions, 1944-1951 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Ledger - interest, receipts, and pledges, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Ledger, 1955 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Loans and mortgages for new church building, 1893-1902 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Papers re loans, 1895-1896 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Loan repayment calculations, 1895-1897 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Loan from George and Margaret Houghton, 1896 August 20 (Box-folder 112/4)
    - Papers re payment of loans, 1896-1897 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Correspondence with A. S. Frank re mortgage and loan, 1897 May-October (Box-folder 5/5)
    - A. G. Klosterman loan and extension, 1899-1905 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - John Green loan and estate, 1894-1899 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Records and correspondence re "Make a Difference!" campaign contributions, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Missionary fund ledger, 1934-1950 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Grants from Neva Moorman request, 1997 August (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Operating statement, 1986 (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Pledges, 1891 (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Pledges, 1895 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Record of pew rentals, 1896-1897 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Pew rental cash book, 1896-1898 (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Pledges and subscriptions, 1898-1899 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Pledge ledger, 1906-1908 (Box-folder Box 126)
    - Pledge register pages, 1903-1904 (Box-folder 127/1)
    - Pew rental ledger, 1899-1902 (Box-folder 5/14)
    - Pledges to roof and tower fund, 1899 May (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Pledges, 1900 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Jubilee fund pledges, 1901 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Paid pledges, 1903 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Pledge for Capital Campaign, 2005 January (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Quarterly reports, 1899 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Quarterly reports, 1901 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Quarterly reports, 1902 (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Quarterly reports, 1903-1905 (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Quarterly reports, 1911 (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Notes re receipts and disbursements, 1925 (Box-folder 6/14)
    - List of rent costs for National Women's Suffrage Association convention, 1905 (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Resolution re benevolence treasurer, 1925 (Box-folder 6/16)
    - Skidmore fund records, 1888-1902 (Box-folder 6/17)
    - Routine financial statements, 1894-1896 (Box-folder 6/18)
    - List of subscribers and assessments, undated (Box-folder 6/19)
    - Subscribers list, undated (Box-folder 6/20)
    - Reverend Horace Lyman's subscription list for building a meeting house, 1850 May 28 (Box-folder 113/1)
    - Subscription list for present building, 1890 (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Subscriptions to new building fund, 1891 (Box-folder 6/22)
    - Subscriptions ledger, 1894 (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Dedication fund subscribers, 1895-1896 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Subscribers and delinquents, 1896-1897 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Unpaid subscriptions to Building Fund, 1897 (Box-folder 112/5)
    - End-of-century subscriptions, 1900-1901 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Suspended accounts, 1995 December 31 (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Treasurer's reports, 1895, undated (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Treasurer's report for 1898, 1899 January 12 (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Treasurer's report for 1899, 1900 January 18 (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Treasurer's report for 1900, 1901 January 17 (Box-folder 7/8)
      Includes attached loan documents.
    - Treasurer's report for 1901, 1902 January 16 (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Treasurer's report for 1902, 1903 January 15 (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Treasurer's report for 1903, 1904 January 1 (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Treasurer's report for 1904, 1905 January 19 (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Treasurer's report, circa 1905 October (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Treasurer's reports, 1921-1926 (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Treasurer's reports, 2011 August-2014 November (Box-folder 7/15)
    - Unpaid rents and pledges, 1894-1898 (Box-folder 7/16)
    - Report of Committee on Uncollected Accounts, 1901 (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Vouchers, 1890-1894; 1905 (Box-folder 8/2)
      Primarily for Building Fund.
    - Vouchers for Building Fund, 1891-1892 (Box-folder 8/3-8/4)
    - Current expense vouchers, 1893 (Box-folder 8/5-8/6)
    - Current expense vouchers, 1894 (Box-folder 8/7-8/8)
    - Current expense vouchers, 1895 (Box-folder 9/1-9/3)
    - Current expense vouchers, 1896 (Box-folder 9/4-9/6)
    - Current expense vouchers, 1897 (Box-folder 9/7-9/8)
    - Vouchers, 1898 (Box-folder 10/1-10/3)
    - Vouchers and deposit book, 1898-1899 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Vouchers, 1899 (Box-folder 10/5-10/6)
    - Vouchers, 1900 (Box-folder 10/7, 11/1)
    - Vouchers, 1901 (Box-folder 11/2-11/3)
    - Vouchers, 1902 (Box-folder 11/4-11/5)
    - Vouchers, 1903 January-April (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Vouchers, 1903 May-December (Box-folder 11/7, 12/1)
    - Vouchers, 1904 (Box-folder 12/2/12/5)
  - Incorporation of First Congregational Church of Portland, 1919 November (Box-folder 12/6)
    Document recording the consolidation of the First Congregational Society of Portland and the First Congregational Church.
  - Janitor applications and recommendations, 1894-1896 (Box-folder 12/7)
  - Listening skill classes, 2012 (Box-folder 12/8)
  - Listening skill project, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 12/9)
  - Forms for Local Church Report, Congregational Year Book, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 12/10)
  - Local Church yearbook reports, 1979-1997 (Box-folder 12/11)
  - Local Church profile, 1986 June 24 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - Local Church profile, 1995 July (Box-folder 13/1)
  - Meetings, Subseries 3
    - Annual meeting minutes and agendas, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Annual meeting programs, 1926; 1931; 1933-1935 (Box-folder 13/3)
    - Annual meeting programs, 1937-1946; 1948 (Box-folder 13/4)
    - Annual meeting programs and agendas, 1948; 1950-1952; 1955 (Box-folder 13/5)
    - Meeting minutes, 1919-1924 (Box-folder 13/6)
      Primarily minutes of annual meetings.
    - Congregational meeting minutes, 1930-1935 (Box-folder 13/7)
    - Congregational meeting minutes, 1947-1959 (Box-folder 13/8)
    - Congregational meeting minutes, 1961-1969 (Box-folder 13/9)
    - Congregational meeting minutes, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 13/10)
    - Congregational meeting minutes, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 13/11)
    - Congregational meeting minutes, 1991-1999 (Box-folder 13/12)
    - Congregational meeting minutes, 2000-2014 (Box-folder 13/13)
    - General officers' meeting minutes, 1966 January 24 (Box-folder 13/14)
    - Officers' orientation meeting minutes, 1970 January 26 (Box-folder 13/15)
    - Trustees' meeting minutes, 1935 June 3 (Box-folder 13/16)
    - Meeting notices and resolutions, 1894-1902 (Box-folder 13/17)
    - "Proceedings of the Business Meetings of the First Congregational Church", 1884 (Box-folder 13/18)
    - Clerk's reports re Congregational meetings, 1921 (Box-folder 13/19)
    - Typescript of January 15, 1914 meeting minutes, undated (Box-folder 13/20)
  - Mission statements, 1987; 1992 (Box-folder 13/21)
  - Mission statement, circa 1995 (Box-folder 13/22)
  - Notes re declining membership and financial situation, circa 1982 (Box-folder 13/23)
  - Notes about worship service, 1962 January (Box-folder 14/1)
  - Organizational charts, 1969; undated (Box-folder 14/2)
  - Organizational chart, circa 1991 (Box-folder 14/3)
  - Organizational chart, circa 1994 (Box-folder 14/4)
  - Policies and procedures, Subseries 4
    - Policies, circa 1965 (Box-folder 14/5)
    - Procedures manual, circa 1994 (Box-folder 14/6)
    - Drafts of procedures manual, circa 2000 (Box-folder 14/7)
    - Proposed building use policies, 2010 July-August (Box-folder 14/8)
    - Suggested procedure for communion service, 1993 November 15 (Box-folder 14/9)
    - "Draft Proposal for a New Approach to Church Governance", 2014 August (Box-folder 14/10)
    - Personnel policies and procedures, 1990 February (Box-folder 14/11)
    - Correspondence and proposals re "Pilgrim" editorial policy, 1987 (Box-folder 14/12)
    - Sample outline, policies and procedures for the prevention of child abuse, 2006 (Box-folder 14/13)
    - Usher's manual, 1968 February 1 (Box-folder 14/14)
    - Usher's manual, 1979 (Box-folder 14/15)
    - Wedding procedure brochures, circa 1960-2000 (Box-folder 14/16)
  - Presentation, "Dream the Dream", 2012 August 15 (Box-folder 14/17)
  - Presentation, "A Governance Structure for the 21st Century", 2014 June 16 (Box-folder 14/18)
  - Presentation, "Unifying Vision, Unifying Plan: First Congregational United Church of Christ", 2013 June 10 (Box-folder 14/19)
    Presentation reporting the findings of a Portland State University Capstone study.
  - Memo re church re-staffing proposal, 1984 April 16 (Box-folder 14/20)
  - Proposal for a fulltime membership coordinator, 1993 (Box-folder 14/21)
  - Questionnaire, 1983 March (Box-folder 14/22)
  - Planning schedule for Real Life Generosity campaign, 2006 (Box-folder 14/23)
  - Record books, Subseries 5
    - Clerk's record book, 1854 April 2 - 1872 June 24 (Box-folder 15/1)
    - Typescript of excerpts from 1854-1872 clerk's record book, undated (Box-folder 15/2)
    - Trustees' minutes book, 1872 September 10 - 1884 December (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Minutes and membership list; constitution, 1885-1898; 1894 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Minutes, reports, and finances, 1890 February - 1897 October (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Handwritten transcript of articles of incorporation and constitution; constitutional amendments and list of members, circa 1895; 1895-1899 (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Trustees' minutes book, 1897-1920 (Box-folder 128/1)
    - Meeting minutes book, 1898-1916 (Box-folder 129/1)
    - Trustees' minutes book, 1922-1936 (Box-folder 17/1)
    - Constitution, by-laws, and amendments; list of members, circa 1923; undated (Box-folder 17/2)
    - Meeting minutes, attendance record, and constitution, 1923 January 1 - 1925 December 14 (Box-folder 17/3)
    - Loose and paperclipped inserts from 1923-1925 record book, 1923-1930 (Box-folder 17/4)
    - Record book, 1926 January - 1930 November (Box-folder 17/5)
      Primarily contains church and council meeting minutes
    - Minutes book, 1932 January 14 - 1946 October 13 (Box-folder 17/6)
    - Loose and paperclipped inserts from 1932-1946 minutes book, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 17/7)
  - Records schedule, 1899 (Box-folder 18/1)
  - Reports, Subseries 6
    - Annual reports, 1930-1945 (Box-folder 18/2)
    - Annual Reports 1948, 1949 January 20 (Box-folder 18/3)
    - Annual Reports 1949, 1950 January 19 (Box-folder 18/4)
    - Annual Reports 1950, 1951 January 18 (Box-folder 18/5)
    - Annual Reports 1951: Our Centennial Year, 1952 January 17 (Box-folder 18/6)
    - Annual Reports 1952, 1953 January 15 (Box-folder 18/7)
    - Annual Reports 1953, 1954 January 21 (Box-folder 18/8)
    - Annual Reports 1954, 1955 January 19 (Box-folder 18/9)
    - Annual Reports 1955, 1956 January 18 (Box-folder 19/1)
    - Annual Reports 1956, 1957 January 15 (Box-folder 19/2)
    - Annual Reports 1957, 1958 January 21 (Box-folder 19/3)
    - Annual Reports 1958, 1959 January 20 (Box-folder 19/4)